

# Vinayak Kasera

Email: Vynkkasera@gmail.com

 SkypeID
 vinu.kasera

 Contact No.:
 +91 9717053210

 DOB:
 23rd Dec 1996

Address: A-4/92, New Kondli, Delhi 110096

**Language** • Hindi (Native Language)

known: • English

**Total** • 4 Years 6 Months

**Experience** 

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and hardworking GIS Consultant with 4 years & 6 Months of experience working with ArcGIS, QGIS, MapInfo Professional, Global Mapper, & Google Earth software's for developing GIS databases, data creation and snapping tolerances. Hands on Several type of data i.e. Village, Town, All India road Network, Highway, Navigation, Regularly demonstrate skill in marketing, basic sales, RFP and customer interaction. Critical thinker continuously looking at ways to improve processes and build business. Excel in editing, Final Report Preparation, Presentation Creating, map production and creating vector property maps.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Office of the Registrar General of India (MHA)

Feb 2021 — Present

*Jr Consultant (MAP-GIS)* 

- Digitization of All India Built-up area.
- Quality checking and Data processing of the Built-up area.
- Data Validation.
- Team Handling.

### **Feedback Infra Private Limited**

Apr 2021 — Dec 2021

Freelancer (GIS)

- "Delhi Katra Expressway" project.
- Preparing Land Acquisition Plan the state of Haryana, Punjab & Jammu.
- Geo-referencing of Cadastral Map & Digitization.

Jan 2020 — Feb 2021

#### **APTARA** (Techbooks International Pvt. Ltd.)

Executive (GIS)

- Geo-referencing of worlds physical, Tectonic, Structure, Basin & Many type of maps in ArcGIS.
- Analysis map difficulty and maptype in research papers of world major Geographical society & Geological society.
- Analysis map of "GEOFACETS".
- QC of Geo referenced maps.

Engineer (GIS)

- Analysis of data on "KPTCL" Project, creating the *Transmission tower* data & *Powerhouse/Substation* data.
- Analysis work Project for the project "MSCDEL" of survey data.
- 25 Members Team manage in "TNSRP" Project for Topographical & Detailed survey.
- Delhi Airport GPR Survey Team Manage.
- "Ground Penetrating Radar" & EPL Survey in Panipat Refinery, Hyderabad Police CCTV, Raipur Smart City, Rohtak Gas Pipeline & Barmer Well Pad.
- Data processing of GPR Data.
- Tenders Evaluation, writing bid proposals, Costing & estimation of various packages, planning the stage wise activity of the projects.
- Interaction with National &International partners for participation in private and public tenders globally.
- Weekly review by CEO and discussion on RFP with solutions.
- Conducting feasibility studies, financial and economic cost benefit evaluations, formulation of project proposals and preparation of project reports.

#### ML Infomap Pvt. Ltd.

**June 2017 — July 2019** 

Database Developer (GIS)

- QA and QC of data on "Kanpur Smart City" & "Ranchi Smart City" GPS Survey
- Golf Course Mapping.
- QA and QC work Project for the project "Lucknow Sewage Network" & GPS Survey.
- QA and QC of data on "BIRAC Project".
- QA and QC of data on "WVI Projects".
- "IOCL" route mapping State of Madhya Pradesh, Gujarat, Bihar & Tamil Nadu.
- Census Data.
- Noida & Greater Noida Master Plan 2021.
- QGIS Training.
- Geo Coding for Delhivery.
- QC work for final map preparation.
- PNGRB Maps.
- Central Potato research institute.
- Command in Indian Election data.
- All India Pincode.
- QA and QC of All India Road Network.
- India Base Map.
- Weekly review by CEO and discussion on RFP with solutions.
- Conducting feasibility studies, financial andeconomic cost benefit evaluations, formulation of projectproposals and preparation of project reports.

## **EDUCATION**

M.sc

Sept 2020 — Present

Uttarakhand Open University, Haldwani

- M.Sc in Geoinformatics.
- Pursuing.

M.sc

**Sept 2017 — Dec 2020** 

Kuruksherta University, Kuruksherta

- M.Sc in Geography.
- Div II with 52%.

B.A.

Shaheed Bhagat Singh College, University of Delhi.

- B.A. in Geography
- Div I with 68.0%
- Final year Project was on "Man & environment relationship on Jabalpur (Madhya Pradesh)"
- I took part in various sports events in college and played lawn tennis, Volleyball, Football and chess. I was also a part of the college team for various cultural events.

Year	Degree	Institute	Percentage / Score
2020	M.Sc(Hons)	Uttarakhand Open University	Pursing
2020	M.Sc (Hons)	Kurukshetra University	52.0%
2017	B.A.(Hons)	Shaheed Bhagat Singh College	68.0 %
2014	12 <sup>th</sup> (CBSE)	Govt, Boys Sr Sec School, New Kondli	73.0 %
2012	10 <sup>th</sup> (CBSE)	Govt, Boys Sr Sec School, New Kondli	7.0 CGPA

#### **SKILLS**

Computer Skills

MS Excel (pivot tables, data visualization) MS Word (styles, templates, version control)

MS PowerPoint

Data Visualization

Social Media (Twitter, Instagram, etc.)

Spreadsheets (Excel & Google Spreadsheets)

Social Skills

Leadership - managed a team of 12 members.

Communication **Decision Making** Time Management

Self-motivation

Teamwork - worked in a team to organize various

College level events. **Conflict Resolution** Adaptability

Creativity

**COMPUTER SOFTWARES** 

ArcGIS - Desktop

**OGIS** 

Mapinfo Professional

Google Earth

Global Mapper Prism(GPR)

MS Office

**INTEREST** 

Sports (Badminton, etc)

Creativity (Free Sketching) Games (Chess) Puzzles

I certify that to the best of my knowledge and belief, this CV correctly describes me, my qualifications, and my experience.

(Vinayak Kasera)